* 

Privacy Policy
==============

While using our Site, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you. Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to name, email address, cookies, usage data. This personal data will be used in accordance with this privacy policy.

The Autism Page complies with data protection legislation including holding an SSL Certificate, registration with the UK Information Commissioners Office and being GDPR compliant.

This policy details how we use personal data and who has access to it.

### **1 Cookies**

**1.1** This site uses cookies, we will ask you for your consent to using these cookies when you first visit our site.

**1.2** Cookies are – small text files that are placed on your machine to help the site provide a better user experience. In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences, store information for things like shopping baskets, and provide anonymised tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics. As a rule, cookies will make your browsing experience better.  However, you may prefer to disable cookies on this site and on others. The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser. We suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at [the About Cookies website](http://www.aboutcookies.org.uk/) which offers guidance for all modern browsers.

**1.3** If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

**1.4** If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

**1.5** When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

**1.6** If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

**1.7** Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.   These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### **2  How we use your personal data**

**2.1** This site uses Google Adsense.  Our current settings within Google Adsense allow for personalised ads which are provided by the commonly used set of ad technology providers. to find out more about how Google manages data in its ad products [follow this link.](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites)

**2.2** The Autism Page is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this cookie & privacy policy.

**2.3** We may process data about your use of our website and services “usage data”. The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is Google Analytics. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services to improve functionality. The legal basis for this processing is through consenting to our cookie usage and only after consent is given our legitimate interests, namely monitoring and improving our website and services.

**2.4** We may process your “account data”. The account data may include your name and email address. The source of the account data is you. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

**2.5** We may process your personal data that are provided in the course of the use of our services “service data”. The service data may include website usage. The source of the service data is you. The service data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

**2.6** We may process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding goods and/or services “enquiry data”. The enquiry data may be processed for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you. The legal basis for this processing is consent.

**2.7** We may process information relating to our customer relationships, including customer contact information “customer relationship data”. The customer relationship data may include your name, your address, your contact details, and information contained in communications between us and you. The source of the customer relationship data is you. The customer relationship data may be processed for the purposes of managing our relationships with customers, communicating with customers, keeping records of those communications and promoting our products and services to customers. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper management of our customer relationships.

**2.8** We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us “transaction data”. The transaction data may include your contact details, your card details and the transaction details. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract and our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

**2.9** We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters “notification data”. The notification data may be processed for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The legal basis for this processing is consent.  If you have subscribed to follow this blog we will retain your e-mail address until you unsubscribe or request we remove your e-mail address by contacting us at [jade@theautismpage.com](mailto:jade@theautismpage.com)

**2.10** We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us “correspondence data”. The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms and comments. The correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users.

**2.11**  When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.  An anonymised string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: [https://automattic.com/privacy/.](https://automattic.com/privacy/) After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

**2.12** If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognise and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.  Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

**2.13** In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 2, we may also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

### **3 Who else has access to your data**

**3.1** This website is Hosted by Siteground and uses the SG Optimizer plugin. You can access their privacy policy here  [https://www.siteground.com/privacy.htm](https://www.siteground.com/privacy.htm)

**3.2** The site is powered by WordPress. By default WordPress does not collect any personal data about visitors, and only collects the data shown on the User Profile screen from registered users.

**3.3** This site uses Akismet. Askimet collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use Akismet anti-spam service. The information collected  typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

**3.4** This site uses the GDPR Cookie Consent Plugin.  Their privacy policy can be accessed here: https://catapultthemes.com/privacy-policy/

**3.5** This site uses the plugin Insert Headers and Footers by wpbeginner.  You can access their privacy policy here: [https://www.wpbeginner.com/privacy-policy/](https://www.wpbeginner.com/privacy-policy/)

**3.6** This site uses the Twitter plugin, their privacy policy is available here [https://twitter.com/en/privacy](https://twitter.com/en/privacy)

**3.7** This site uses Updraft Plus to back up the site you can view their privacy policy here – [https://updraftplus.com/data-protection-and-privacy-centre/](https://updraftplus.com/data-protection-and-privacy-centre/)

**3.8** The back ups created by Updraft plus are stored with Google Drive, their privacy policy is here – [https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites?hl=en-GB&gl=uk](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites?hl=en-GB&gl=uk)

**3.9** This site uses the Easy Digital Downloads plugin more information can be viewed here – [https://docs.easydigitaldownloads.com/](https://docs.easydigitaldownloads.com/)

**3.10** This site also uses the W3 Total Cache plug in and WP Optimise plug in.

**3.11** Defender Security, monitoring and hack protection plug in is used. This site may be using third-party cloud storage to store backups of its audit logs where personal information is collected. This site creates and stores an activity log that capture the IP address, username, email address and tracks user activity (like when a user makes a comment). Information will be stored locally for 30 days and remotely for 1 year. Information on remote logs cannot be cleared for security purposes.

**3.12** This site uses Mailchimp to manage its email subscriptions.  You can see their privacy policy [here.](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

**3.13** This site uses 404 page plugin. You can view their privacy policy [here](https://petersplugins.com/plugin-privacy-information/).

**3.14** This site uses Ads.txt manager developed by [10up](https://10up.com/).

**3.15** This site uses the [Meta Box](https://metabox.io/) plugin.

**3.16** This site uses the One Signal Push Notifications Plug in to send push notifications, see their privacy policy here: [https://onesignal.com/privacy](https://onesignal.com/privacy)

**3.17** This site uses the Smush plugin. Smush does not interact with end users on this website. The only input option Smush has is to a newsletter subscription for site admins only.

3.18 This site uses a Pipdig theme, you can access their privacy policy here: [https://www.pipdig.co/privacy/](https://www.pipdig.co/privacy/)

3.19: This site uses the Google Web Stories Plugin their privacy policy is here – [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)

### **4\. Analytics**

**4.1** This site uses Google Analytics to monitor user statistics, you can access their privacy policy here: [https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites?hl=en-GB&gl=uk](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites?hl=en-GB&gl=uk)

**4.2** This site uses the Monster Insight Plugin to access Google Analytics.  The Monster Insights privacy policy can be accessed here: [https://www.monsterinsights.com/privacy-policy/](https://www.monsterinsights.com/privacy-policy/)

**4.3** This site uses Jetpack, their privacy policy can be located here: [https://jetpack.com/support/privacy/](https://jetpack.com/support/privacy/)

**4.4** This site uses the Yoast SEO plug in you can view their privacy policy here – [https://yoast.com/privacy-policy/](https://yoast.com/privacy-policy/)

### **5\. Further information**

**5.1** The site owner is Jade Page who is also the Data Protection Officer

**5.2**  The Autism Page was formally known as About ASD but was re-branded in December 2018.

**5.3** The website address for The Autism Page is: [https://www.theautismpage.com](https://www.theautismpage.com/)

**5.4** You can contact The Autism Page by email: [Jade@theautismpage.com](mailto:Jade@theautismpage.com)

**5.5** You have the right to see what personal data of yours we hold, and you can also ask us to correct any factual errors. Provided the legal minimum period has elapsed, you can also ask us to erase your records.

**5.6** In order to protect user security this site has an SSL Certificate

5.7 The Autism Page complies with data protection legislation including registration with the UK Information Commissioners Office and being GDPR compliant.

**5.**8 This policy may change from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from July 2018. \[updated January 2021\]

Number of items in basket: 0

* Your basket is empty.
* Total: £0.00

### Search

Hi my name is Jade and I am a married mum of two boys (9 & 11). We are UK based in the West Country between Bristol and Bath. Stick around while I share information and resources related to autism that have been helpful to us since my eldest was diagnosed at age 2. Hopefully you will find something that can help you.

### Popular Posts:

### LEGO/Brick Therapy Resources

© 2024 [The Autism Page](https://www.theautismpage.com/)

[×](javascript:void(0))
